So, let's walk through the model.
让我们讲解一下这个模型
I've kept the overarching themes here on the left.
我在左侧保留了对每一行的解释
So, you can see what is the motivation for each of these sections.
以便于你理解这些部分的意义
We start with the number of opportunities we expect the person to close annually.
首先预期一名销售人员一年的成单量
Average price per unit is the average price per unit or product for manufacturing.
平均价格/件产品 是指每件产品或制造产品的平均价格
If you work in a sales SaaS company,
如果在软件即服务 (SaaS) 公司
this would be the average price per seat.
则表示每个软件账号的平均价格
Average units per opportunity is the average number of
平均产品件数/订单 是指
units you can expect to sell per opportunity.
预期每笔订单中的平均产品数量
Average contracts month per opportunity is the average length
平均合同月数/订单 是指
of time in months that sales contract can be for.
销售合同期限的平均月数
Next, we get to the average opportunity size.
接着计算订单平均规模
You just take the product of these three numbers,
利用这三项数据 —
average price per unit,
平均价格/件产品、
average units per opportunity and average
平均产品件数/订单、
contract months per opportunity to get this number of bookings.
以及平均合同月数/订单 来计算订货单数量
This is the average booking size we expect this salesperson to create on an annual basis.
这是我们预期一位销售人员一年创造的平均订货单规模
Next, we see how we are going to get to these booking sites.
接着 我们来看看达到这些订货单规模的过程
We start with the assumption that the center ramp or the length of time we can
首先假设销售人员正式工作后的上手时间
expect the new seller to reach full productivity after being hired is three months.
也就是达到正常销售效率的时间 为三个月
So, we have the projector and hire date here and we use dummy coding.
这里列出了预计聘用日期 并且使用虚拟编码
Dummy coding refers to when you give a value of zero or one to
虚拟编码是指在单元格内输入值 0 或 1
a sale because it means something's got to represent something has happened.
用来表示发生的情况
It's kind of one and zero are dummies for the presence of something happening.
0 和 1 就是用来表示所发生情况的两个虚拟编码
So, in the sales hiring schedule,
对于聘用销售人员的时间表
we're trying to create dummy coding for the projected hire date and after that,
我们将建立虚拟编码来表示预计聘用日期
indicating a one for the person having been hired.
用 1 来表示已经聘用到合适的人选
For this, we use two XOR functions.
这里用到两个 Excel 函数
One is end of month and the other is today. Let's start with today.
一个是月末日期的函数 另一个是今天日期的函数 首先是今天的日期
So, for sales person one, say,
对于销售人员 1
we are going to hire them on 12/16.
假设聘用日期是 12/16
So, we start with the today function just says okay.
先输入今天日期的函数 (TODAY)
Whatever today's date is,
无论今天日期是几号
just add 30 days to it.
加上 30 天
Well, since I'm doing the recording on 11/16,
我是在 11/16 这天录音的
it is just adding 30 days to that and so on.
对这个日期加上 30 天 如此类推
Here, we're adding 60 days to it and here we are adding 90 days to it.
然后对原日期加上 60 天 再对原日期加上 90 天
End of month allows you to state that today date
使用月末函数(EOMONTH)时 先确定今天的日期
and add months to that date and give that final date.
然后对该日期加上若干个月 得出月末日期
So, today's date is 11/16 and is adding
比如 今天日期是 11/16
zero months to it but it's giving me the end of the month, which is 11/30.
加上零个月 得出月末日期是 11/30
It does the same thing,
这一格也是同样的公式
giving it a one-month laps,
相隔一个月、
two-month laps and a three-month laps.
相隔两个月、相隔三个月
So, now we can see that the hiring schedule shows that once a person has hired,
这个聘用时间表指出 一旦聘用到合适的人选
a month from then,
一个月之后
they will be employed and available to start generating leads,
他们入职并开始开发潜在客户
and that's what this table is showing.
这就是这份表格要告诉我们的信息
For the center productivity schedule,
对于销售人员生产力时间表
we borrow the end of month function again and get
我们再次沿用月末函数
three months for every month from today.
从今天起的一个月之后再给三个月时间
So, because we are trying to generate
因为我们想预计
the schedule when the seller is going to be productive,
新销售人员上手达到正常生产力的时间
we want to give the seller three months of ramp time.
假设 我们给新聘用的销售人员三个月的上手时间
So, starting from today,
從今天算起
end of the month of today's month,
今天所在月份的月末
just add three months to that.
再加上三个月
So, that's what end of month does here.
就是这个月末函数的含义
We're just giving it C14,
代入单元格 C14 的值
which is this month,
也就是这一个月
this date here and it's adding three months to that,
在这个日期的基础加上三个月
same here and use the dummy coding to create
这里也一样 然后用虚拟编码
the productivity schedule that shows three months since the person was hired,
创建生产力时间表 用于表示销售人员入职三个月之后
the person is going to be productive or not.
是否能够达到正常的生产力效率
This matrix describes the productive discussion.
这个指标表示的就是生产力时间表
Finally, we get to our projections for when a seller
最后 我们预计了新销售人员
will be productive and the projected bookings based on that.
何时会达到正常的生产力 并在此基础上预测订货量
Since we only need the bookings the seller will generate per month,
由于我们只需要得出每位销售人员每个月会带来的订货量
we're trying to calculate that dollar amount per month.
或者说 需要计算每个月的订货金额 (以美元为单位)
We need to multiply the productivity dummy variable,
因而 需要把这个生产力虚拟代码的变量乘以…
here with the projected average booking that we expect based on this number.
…基于我们刚才预计的平均订货量
So, let me break that down.
仔细分析一下
So, this is telling us that,
意思就是
start with this booking number,
用订货单金额
130,000 per person times
即每人 130,000 美元 乘以…
the number of opportunities the person will be generating per month,
…该销售人员每月带来的订单数量
that's this number, and multiply that with this value,
也就是这个数字 再乘以这个值
which is whether the person is productive or not.
也就是销售人员是否有正常生产力的虚拟代码
So, it generates that projected booking per person for
得出每人在某个月的预计订货量
that month based on this and then we can get our total bookings at the bottom.
再在最后一行得出预计订货量总数
I made a copy of the CSV,
我在下页提供了一份同样的 CSV 文件
so you can look at the CSV file yourself too.
你可以参照这个 CSV 文件
Feel free to watch this video again,
尤其在回看这个视频时
slowly, as you follow along with the file on your computer.
可以参照文件中的内容